The Thomas and Ryan Families
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- 2.1.3.3.1
  - Pherbia Thomas Thornburg [sister of Lowell Thomas], 1917 - 1936; 5 (Box 1520)
    - Note: AWARD PRIZES AT CHINA ESSAY CONTEST DINNER Eighty distinguished guests, all of them especially interested in China and in Far Eastern affairs, gathered at the Ford Motor pavilion on September 18 for a formal dinner in honor of the Contest's judges, prizewinners, and the contest's financial sponsor, W.D. Pawley. Lowell Thomas presented his newscast as part of the banquet, over which he presided. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford pavilion, acted as host. Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, contest director, presented the first three prizes to Minerva S. Desing of Collingswood, N.J.; Richard E. Curl of Edison, O.; and Helen Averitt of Pasadena, Calif. The spacious Ford Executive Lounge was especially decorated with Chinese screens, tapestries, modern paintings and statuary. Table decorations were Chinese junks, night-blooming water lilies in natural wood bowls, and silk Chinese and American flags. Costumed Chinese girls gave corsages to women guests and boutonnieres to men. Guests entered through a Dragon Gate; as they sat at table they could see, through the great glass wall of the Lounge, the Ford pavilion terrace which for the occasion had been transformed into a Chinese garden at Autumn Festival time, with trees, a scenic backdrop, a compound wall, gay lanterns, and dainty costumed Chinese girls having tea. A Chinese orchestra played. Favors, supplied by the China Essay Contest, were handsome souvenir books especially published and bound in brocade treaty silk. In this photo (left to right) are: Lowell Thomas, Rear Admiral H. E. Yarnell and Pearl Buck, 12
    - Photograph from China Essay Contest Dinner with Note 5.13, 13
    - Note: AWARD PRIZES AT CHINA ESSAY CONTEST DINNER Eighty distinguished guests, all of them especially interested in China and in Far Eastern affairs, gathered at the Ford Motor pavilion on September 18 for a formal dinner in honor of the Contest's judges, prizewinners, and the contest's financial sponsor, W.D. Pawley. Lowell Thomas presented his newscast as part of the banquet, over which he presided. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford pavilion, acted as host. Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, contest director, presented the first three prizes to Minerva S. Desing of Collingswood, N.J.; Richard E. Curl of Edison, O.; and Helen Averitt of Pasadena, Calif. The spacious Ford Executive Lounge was especially decorated with Chinese screens, tapestries, modern paintings and statuary. Table decorations were Chinese junks, night-blooming water lilies in natural wood bowls, and silk Chinese and American flags. Costumed Chinese girls gave corsages to women guests and boutonnieres to men. Guests entered through a Dragon Gate; as they sat at table they could see, through the great glass wall of the Lounge, the Ford pavilion terrace which for the occasion had been transformed into a Chinese garden at Autumn Festival time, with trees, a scenic backdrop, a compound wall, gay lanterns, and dainty costumed Chinese girls having tea. A Chinese orchestra played. Favors, supplied by the China Essay Contest, were handsome souvenir books especially published and bound in brocade treaty silk. In this photo (left to right) are: Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, W. D. Pawley, Mrs. William Brown Meloney (from Newsweek magazine), Rear Admiral Yarnell (in back) and Lowell Thomas, 14
    - Photograph from China Essay Contest Dinner with Note 5.15, 15
    - Note: AWARD PRIZES AT CHINA ESSAY CONTEST DINNER Eighty distinguished guests, all of them especially interested in China and in Far Eastern affairs, gathered at the Ford Motor pavilion on September 18 for a formal dinner in honor of the Contest's judges, prizewinners, and the contest's financial sponsor, W.D. Pawley. Lowell Thomas presented his newscast as part of the banquet, over which he presided. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford pavilion, acted as host. Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, contest director, presented the first three prizes to Minerva S. Desing of Collingswood, N.J.; Richard E. Curl of Edison, O.; and Helen Averitt of Pasadena, Calif. The spacious Ford Executive Lounge was especially decorated with Chinese screens, tapestries, modern paintings and statuary. Table decorations were Chinese junks, night-blooming water lilies in natural wood bowls, and silk Chinese and American flags. Costumed Chinese girls gave corsages to women guests and boutonnieres to men. Guests entered through a Dragon Gate; as they sat at table they could see, through the great glass wall of the Lounge, the Ford pavilion terrace which for the occasion had been transformed into a Chinese garden at Autumn Festival time, with trees, a scenic backdrop, a compound wall, gay lanterns, and dainty costumed Chinese girls having tea. A Chinese orchestra played. Favors, supplied by the China Essay Contest, were handsome souvenir books especially published and bound in brocade treaty silk. In this photo (left to right) are: Rear Admiral H. E. Yarnell, Mrs. William Brown Meloney, and Lowell Thomas, 16
    - Photograph from China Essay Contest Dinner with Note 5.17, 17
    - Note: AWARD PRIZES AT CHINA ESSAY CONTEST DINNER Eighty distinguished guests, all of them especially interested in China and in Far Eastern affairs, gathered at the Ford Motor pavilion on September 18 for a formal dinner in honor of the Contest's judges, prizewinners, and the contest's financial sponsor, W.D. Pawley. Lowell Thomas presented his newscast as part of the banquet, over which he presided. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford pavilion, acted as host. Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, contest director, presented the first three prizes to Minerva S. Desing of Collingswood, N.J.; Richard E. Curl of Edison, O.; and Helen Averitt of Pasadena, Calif. The spacious Ford Executive Lounge was especially decorated with Chinese screens, tapestries, modern paintings and statuary. Table decorations were Chinese junks, night-blooming water lilies in natural wood bowls, and silk Chinese and American flags. Costumed Chinese girls gave corsages to women guests and boutonnieres to men. Guests entered through a Dragon Gate; as they sat at table they could see, through the great glass wall of the Lounge, the Ford pavilion terrace which for the occasion had been transformed into a Chinese garden at Autumn Festival time, with trees, a scenic backdrop, a compound wall, gay lanterns, and dainty costumed Chinese girls having tea. A Chinese orchestra played. Favors, supplied by the China Essay Contest, were handsome souvenir books especially published and bound in brocade treaty silk. In this photo (left to right) are: Mrs. William Brown Meloney, Lowell Thomas and Pearl Buck, 18
    - Photograph from China Essay Contest Dinner with Note 5.19, 19
    - Note: AWARD PRIZES AT CHINA ESSAY CONTEST DINNER Eighty distinguished guests, all of them especially interested in China and in Far Eastern affairs, gathered at the Ford Motor pavilion on September 18 for a formal dinner in honor of the Contest's judges, prizewinners, and the contest's financial sponsor, W.D. Pawley. Lowell Thomas presented his newscast as part of the banquet, over which he presided. Fred L. Black, director of the Ford pavilion, acted as host. Pherbia Thomas Thornburg, contest director, presented the first three prizes to Minerva S. Desing of Collingswood, N.J.; Richard E. Curl of Edison, O.; and Helen Averitt of Pasadena, Calif. The spacious Ford Executive Lounge was especially decorated with Chinese screens, tapestries, modern paintings and statuary. Table decorations were Chinese junks, night-blooming water lilies in natural wood bowls, and silk Chinese and American flags. Costumed Chinese girls gave corsages to women guests and boutonnieres to men. Guests entered through a Dragon Gate; as they sat at table they could see, through the great glass wall of the Lounge, the Ford pavilion terrace which for the occasion had been transformed into a Chinese garden at Autumn Festival time, with trees, a scenic backdrop, a compound wall, gay lanterns, and dainty costumed Chinese girls having tea. A Chinese orchestra played. Favors, supplied by the China Essay Contest, were handsome souvenir books especially published and bound in brocade treaty silk. In this photo (left to right) are: Richard E. Curl, Minerva F. Desing, Helen Averitt and Lowell Thomas, 20
  - Pherbia Thomas Thornburg [sister of Lowell Thomas], 1933 - 1946; 6 (Box 1520)
    - [Two men and three women on boat], 1
    - [Pherbia Thomas Thornberg and man on skis], 2
    - [Pherbia Thomas Thornberg and man on skis], 3
    - [Pherbia Thomas Thornberg and man on skis], 4
    - [Portrait of Pherbia Thomas Thornberg], 5
    - [Portrait of Pherbia Thomas Thornberg], 6
    - [Portrait of Pherbia Thomas Thornberg with white background], [3 copies], 7
    - Canton [aerial photograph], 8
    - Verso: Canton, 8-verso
    - [Many sailboats in harbor, 9
    - Amoy [aerial photograph], 10
    - Verso: Amoy, 10-verso
    - Amoy [aerial photograph], 11
    - Verso: Amoy, 11-verso
    - Wau lsien [?], 12
    - Verso: Wau lsien [?], [aerial photograph], 12-verso
    - Gorges [aerial photograph, plane in view], 13
    - Verso: Gorges, 13-verso
    - Lungwo [?], [aerial photograph], 14
    - Verso: Lungwo [?], 14-verso
    - Lungwo [?], [aerial photograph], 15
    - Verso: Lungwo [?], 15-verso
    - [Asian architecture], 16
    - [Asian architecture], 17
    - [Asian architecture], 18
    - [Pherbia Thomas Thornberg seated with asian woman], 19
    - [Bridge over river with field in foreground], 20
    - [Elephant statue], 21
  - Pherbia Thomas Thornburg [sister of Lowell Thomas] and nephew Lowell Thomas, Jr., circa 1933; 7 (Box 1520)
    - Pherbia Thomas Thornburg [sister of Lowell Thomas] and nephew Lowell Thomas, Jr. [in odd tennis or athletic clothing], 1
  - Family dogs [includes color photographs], undated; 8 (Box 1520)
    - Fran and Peppersass, dog that ripped pants off of local Congressman - Ralph Gwinn, 1
    - Note: Fran and Peppersass, dog that ripped pants off of local Congressman - Ralph Gwinn, 2
    - [Older Lowell Thomas and Frances Ryan Thomas at Hammersley Hill with three dogs], 3
    - [Furry white dog (Alaskan Eskimo Dog?)], 4
    - [Woman holding Furry white dog (Alaskan Eskimo Dog?)], 5
    - [Another woman holding Furry white dog (Alaskan Eskimo Dog?)], 6
    - [Boy holding Furry white dog (Alaskan Eskimo Dog?)], 7
    - [Small Dog sitting on table (Cocker Spaniel?)], 8
    - [Small Dog on chair with chiefs had holding a hot dog (Cocker Spaniel?)], 9